Guide to the Stanford University, Museum, Committee for Art, Stanford Portfolio Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Museum, Committee for Art, Stanford portfolio records
1970-1980
SC0264
Stanford University. Museum of Art. Committee for Art.
1.25 Linear feet
Research files of Hametia Fielder King relating to the design and construction of the Stanford Museum of Art, used by the Museum docent program for their "Stanford Portfolio." A number of the files pertain to George Washington Percy and Ernest Ransome and there are some files pertaining to other campus buildings. Materials include notes and correspondence of Mrs. King, photocopied historic sources, and contemporary brochures, articles, and clippings.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of The Committee for Art, 1981.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Description of the Collection
Research files of Hametia Fielder King relating to the design and construction of the Stanford Museum of Art, used by the Museum docent program for their "Stanford Portfolio." A number of the files pertain to George Washington Percy and Ernest Ransome and there are some files pertaining to other campus buildings. Materials include notes and correspondence of Mrs. King, photocopied historic sources, and contemporary brochures, articles, and clippings.
Access Terms
King, Hametia Fielder.; King, Hametia Fielder.; Percy, George Washington.; Percy, George Washington.; Ransome, Ernest.; Ransome, Ernest.; Stanford University -- General subdivision--Buildings.;; Stanford University. Museum of Art. Committee for Art.
Collection Contents
- Records
  - Hametia Fielder King, “The Patrons and the Professionals; the planning, design and construction of the Leland Stanford Junior Museum. Part One: 1884-1906” (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Transcript of Stanford Historical Society meeting Nov. 6, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Gifts generated by museum building research (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Concrete in fine arts, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence with American Concrete Institute (Mrs. King), 1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Excerpts from 1906-07 volume of Architect and Engineer of California (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Interview notes re museum structure (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Milestones in development of concrete (various sources) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Texts containing references to Stanford Museum structure (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Earthquake – general and museum (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Museum press quotes (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Architects and engineers: Hamilton, Percy, Ransome, Babson (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Architects biographies: Hamilton, Hodges, Schultze, Bugbee and Percy (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Sequence of events – design team, construction of museum, day-to-day operations (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Olmsted (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Olmsted – Codman - Austin (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - G. W. Percy – career (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Percy and family (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Ransome and family (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Richardson – Coolidge – museum design; correspondence with Max Ferro, 1973-75 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Winery (Christian Brothers in Napa Valley) (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Letter from Bruce Ricks and various sources re Stanford lands (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Bronze doors (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Greece / Heinrich Schliemann [correspondence with Greek officials re design of Stanford museum] (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Classical Revival architectural style (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Rotunda (marble, etc.) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Cornerstone [of the museum] (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Mosaics: Paoletti (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Sculpture for museum portico (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Stanford’s interest in architecture and building (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Sacramento house / Washington house / Port Washington house (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Nob Hill house (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Campus – assorted sources (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Escondite Cottage / Tower House (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Other Stanford [family member]’s homes (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Stanford University campus buildings in general (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Tour of Percy building: Museum (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Tour of Percy building: S.F. Unitarian Church (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Tour – summary of talk by Elizabeth K. Thompson, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Jordan, Days of a Man – notes from (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Elliott’s book – notes from (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Walker, F. A. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Kevin Starr on Stanford museum (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Argonaut – groundbreaking for museum (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Live Oak – copies of articles from (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - List of plans and book lists (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Very early research (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Earthquake (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Study materials (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, miscellaneous, 1973-74 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous sources (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous notes and sources (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Photocopied sources (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Sources on Ransome concrete methods (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - National Archaeological Museum Collection of Sculpture, a Catalogue (Athens 1968) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Book in Greek, probably on Greek antiquities (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Print of Christian Brothers Winery building, St. Helena [drawing by Titus 1972] (Box 4, Folder 3)